THORIN:
We'll camp here for the night.
Fili, Kili, look after the ponies.
Make sure you stay with them.
A farmer and his family used to live here.
THORIN: Oin, Gloin. Get a fire going.
OIN: Aye.
Right you are.
I think it would be wiser to move on.
We could make for the Hidden Valley.
I have told you already...
...I will not go near that place.
Why not? The Elves could help us.
We could get food, rest, advice.
THORIN:
I do not need their advice.
We have a map that we cannot read.
Lord Elrond could help us.
Help?
A dragon attacks Erebor.
What help came from the Elves?
Orcs plunder Moria...
...desecrate our sacred halls.
The Elves looked on and did nothing.
And you ask me to seek out the very people
who betrayed my grandfather.
Who betrayed my father.
You are neither of them.
I did not give you that map and key
for you to hold onto the past.
I did not know that they were yours to keep.
Everything all right?
Gandalf, where are you going?
GANDALF: To seek the company of the
only one around here who's got any sense.
- And who's that?
GANDALF: Myself, Mr. Baggins.
I've had enough of Dwarves for one day.
Come on, Bombur, we're hungry.
Is he coming back?
[DWARVES CHATTERING]
He's been a long time.
- Who?
- Gandalf.
He's a Wizard. He does as he chooses.
Here, do us a favor. Take this to the lads.
Stop it. You've had plenty.
GLOIN: Aye, it's not a bad stew, Bombur.
I've had worse.
NORI:
Dori could've cooked it. Ha-ha-ha.
DORI:
Hilarious.
What's the matter?
- We're supposed to be looking after the ponies.
- Only we've encountered a slight problem.
KILI:
We had 16.
FILI:
Now there's 14.
KILI:
Daisy and Bungo are missing.
Well, that's not good. Ha, ha.
And that is not good at all.
Shouldn't we tell Thorin?
Uh, no. Let's not worry him.
As our official burglar,
we thought you might like to look into it.
Well, uh....
- Look, something big uprooted these trees.
- That was our thinking.
- It's something very big
and possibly quite dangerous.
Hey.
There's a light.
Over here.
Stay down.
[GRUNTING AND LAUGHTER]
What is it?
Trolls.
Oh.
[PONIES NEIGHING]
He's got Myrtle and Minty.
I think they're gonna eat them.
We have to do something.
Yes, you should.
Mountain Trolls are slow and stupid,
and you're so small, they'll never see you.
It's perfectly safe. We'll be behind you.
If you run into trouble, hoot twice
like a barn owl and once like a brown owl.
BILBO: Twice like a barn owl.
No, twice like a brown-- Once like a--
Like a-- Are you sure this is a good idea?
BERT:
Mutton yesterday, mutton today...
...and, blimey, if it don't look like
mutton again tomorrow.
WILLIAM:
Quit your griping.
These ain't sheep. These is fresh nags.
Oh! I don't like horse. I never have.
Not enough fat on them.
Well, it's better than leathery old farmer.
All skin and bone, he was. I'm still
picking bits of him out of me teeth.
[TOM SNEEZES]
Well, that's lovely, that is. A floater.
WILLIAM:
Might improve the flavor.
Ah. There's more where that came from.
- Oh, no, you don't!
TOM: Ow!
[TOM WHIMPERING]
Sit down!
[SNEEZES]
[TOM BLOWING NOSE]
Well, I hope you're gonna gut these nags.
I don't like the stinky parts.
- Ow!
- I said sit down.
I'm starving!
Now, are we having horse tonight or what?
BERT: Shut your cakehole.
You'll eat what I give you.
WILLIAM: How come he's the cook?
Everything tastes the same.
Everything tastes like chicken.
TOM:
Except the chicken.
WILLIAM:
What tastes like fish!
I'm just saying,
a little appreciation would be nice.
[PONY NEIGHS]
Oh. "Thank you very much, Bert.
Lovely stew, Bert."
- How hard is that?
- Shh. Shh, shh. Shh.
BERT:
Just needs a sprinkle of squirrel dung.
Here, that's my grog.
[TOM WHIMPERS]
Sorry. Ow!
Ooh. That is beautifully balanced, that is.
Wrap your laughing gear around that, eh?
Good, isn't it?
[BERT CHUCKLES]
That's why I'm the cook.
[WILLIAM GRUNTS]
WILLIAM: Oh, me guts are grumbling.
I got to snaffle something.
- Flesh, I need flesh.
TOM: Ah! Ah!
[TOM BLOWS NOSE]
[SCREAMS]
Blimey!
Bert. Bert!
Look what's come out of me hooter.
It's got arms and legs and everything.
BERT:
What is it?
I don't know.
But I don't like the way it wriggles around.
What are you, then? An oversized squirrel?
I'm a burglar-- Uh, Hobbit.
A burglarobbit?
Can we cook him?
We can try.
He wouldn't make more than a mouthful.
Not when he's skinned and boned.
Perhaps there's more burglarobbits
around these parts.
Might be enough for a pie.
- Grab him!
TOM: He's too quick.
WILLIAM:
Right. Come here, you little--
Gotcha.
Are there any more of you little fellas
hiding where you shouldn't?
No.
He's lying.
- No, I'm not!
- Hold his toes over the fire.
Make him squeal!
[SQUEALS]
Drop him!
You what?
I said...
...drop him.
[GROWLS]
[BILBO YELLS]
[ALL YELLING]
[TOM SQUEALS]