[IN ENGLISH]
Welcome, Thorin, son of Thrain.
I do not believe we have met.
You have your grandfather's bearing.
I knew Thror
when he ruled Under the Mountain.
Indeed? He made no mention of you.
[SPEAKING IN ELVISH]
GLOIN:
What is he saying?
Does he offer us insult?
No, Master Gloin, he's offering you food.
[ALL MURMURING]
Well, in that case, lead on.
BOFUR:
Hey. Come on.
Try it. Just a mouthful.
I don't like green food.
Where's the meat?
[GROWLS]
Have they got any chips?
Kind of you to invite us.
Not really dressed for dinner.
Well, you never are.
[GANDALF CHUCKLES]
[DWARVES CHUCKLING]
[CHUCKLES]
This is Orcrist, the Goblin-cleaver.
A famous blade...
...forged by the High Elves of the West,
my kin.
May it serve you well.
And this is Glamdring...
...the Foehammer.
Sword of the King of Gondolin.
These swords were made for
the Goblin Wars of the First Age.
I wouldn't bother, laddie. Swords are
named for the great deeds they do in war.
What are you saying,
my sword hasn't seen battle?
I'm not actually sure it is a sword.
More of a letter opener, really.
How did you come by these?
We found them in a Troll-hoard
on the Great East Road...