Where's Bilbo? Where's the Hobbit?
[BILBO GRUNTING]
There!
THORIN:
Get him!
Aah!
- Grab my hand!
- Bilbo!
DORI: Ori, be careful!
ORI: Take it!
DWALIN: I've got you, lad.
ORI: Grab on! Grab on!
[GRUNTING]
Come on. Get him.
GLOIN:
Come on, lad. Up you get.
I thought we'd lost our burglar.
He's been lost ever since he left home.
He should never have come.
He has no place amongst us.
Dwalin!
DWALIN: lt looks safe enough.
THORIN: Search to the back.
Caves in the mountain
are seldom unoccupied.
DWALIN:
There's nothing here.
Right, then. Let's get a fire started.
No. No fires. Not in this place.
Get some sleep.
We start at first light.
We were to wait in the mountains
until Gandalf joined us.
- That was the plan.
- Plans change.
Bofur, take the first watch.