Wait!
My precious. Wait!
Gollum, gollum!
[FOOTSTEPS]
GANDALF:
Quick, quick!
This way.
[GASPS]
DORI: Come on.
GANDALF: Come on, come on. Quickly.
Right, good!
[SCREAMS]
Baggins!
Thief!
Curse it and crush it!
We hates it forever!
Five, six, seven, eight.
Bifur. Bofur. That's 10.
Fili, Kili! That's 12.
And Bombur. That makes 13.
Where's Bilbo?
Where is our Hobbit?
Where is our Hobbit?!?
DWALIN:
Curse the Halfling! Now he's lost?
GLOIN:
I thought he was with Dori!
- Don't blame me!
- Well, where did you last see him?
I think I saw him slip away
when they first collared us.
GANDALF:
And what happened, exactly?
- Tell me!
- I'll tell you what happened.
Master Baggins saw his chance
and he took it.
He has thought of nothing
but his soft bed and his warm hearth...
...since first he stepped out of his door.
We will not be seeing our Hobbit again.
He is long gone.
No. He isn't.
Bilbo Baggins.
I have never been so glad
to see anyone in my life.
Bilbo. We'd given you up.
How on earth
did you get past the Goblins?
How, indeed.
[CHUCKLES]
Well, what does it matter? He's back.
It matters. I want to know.
Why did you come back?
Look, I know you doubt me.
I know you always have.
And you're right, I often think of Bag End.
I miss my books.
And my armchair and my garden.
See, that's where I belong.
That's home.
And that's why I came back. Because...
...you don't have one. A home.
It was taken from you.
But I will help you take it back if I can.