Now there is only one.
You need to reach the mountain
before the last days of autumn.
Before Durin's Day falls, yes.
You are running out of time.
Which is why we must
go through Mirkwood.
A darkness lies upon that forest.
Fell things creep beneath those trees.
There is an alliance
between the Orcs of Moria...
...and the Necromancer in Dol Guldur.
I would not venture there,
except in great need.
We will take the Elven Road.
That path is still safe.
BEORN:
"Safe"?
The Wood Elves of Mirkwood
are not like their kin.
They're less wise and more dangerous.
But it matters not.
What do you mean?
These lands are crawling with Orcs.
Their numbers are growing.
And you are on foot.
You will never reach the forest alive.
I don't like Dwarves.
They're greedy--
...and blind.
Blind to the lives of those
they deem lesser than their own.
But Orcs I hate more.
What do you need?
BEORN:
Go now. While you have the light.