ELROS: Galion, you old rogue,
we're running out of drink.
These empty barrels should have been
sent back to Esgaroth hours ago.
The bargeman will be waiting for them.
GALION: Say what you like about our ill-
tempered king. He has excellent taste in wine.
Come, Elros, try it.
ELROS:
I have the Dwarves in my charge.
GALION:
They're locked up. Where can they go? Ha, ha.
BOFUR:
I'll wager the sun is on the rise.
Must be nearly dawn.
We're never gonna reach
the mountain, are we?
Not stuck in here, you're not.
Bilbo!
KILI: What?
[DWARVES CHATTER]
Shh! There are guards nearby!
THORIN: Close the doors, it'll buy us more time.
- All right, Nori.
THORIN: Up the stairs.
DWALIN: You first. Ori.
BILBO:
Not that way. Down here. Follow me.
- Go.
OIN: Easy, now.
[SNORING]
[WHISPERING]
This way.