MAN 1: These children are starving.
MAN 2: We need food.
MAN 1: We won't last three days.
PERCY: Bard...
- ...we don't have enough.
- Do what you can, Percy.
PERCY:
It'll be all right. Don't worry.
WOMAN:
We need more water.
The children, the wounded
and the women come first.
MAN 3:
Here you are.
BARD:
Good morning, Alfrid.
What news from the night watch?
All quiet, sire. Not much to report.
Nothing gets past me.
Except an army of Elves, it would seem.
My Lord Thranduil, we did not look...
- ...to see you here.
- I heard you needed aid.
[CHATTERING]
Here you go.
MAN 1:
Pass it back.
MAN 2:
Another one.
BARD:
You have saved us.
I do not know how to thank you.
Your gratitude is misplaced.
I did not come on your behalf.
I came to reclaim something of mine.
There are gems in the Mountain
that I, too, desire.
White gems of pure starlight.
The White Gems of Lasgalen.
I know an Elf Lord who will pay
a pretty price for these.
BARD:
Wait! Please wait!
You would go to war
over a handful of gems?
The heirlooms of my people
are not lightly forsaken.
We are allies in this.
My people...
...also have a claim
upon the riches in that Mountain.
Let me speak with Thorin.
You would try to reason with the Dwarf?
To avoid war?
Yes.
GLOIN:
Not a bad night's work.
Come on.
Hail, Thorin, son of Thrain.
We are glad to find you alive beyond hope.
Why do you come to the gates of the
King under the Mountain armed for war?
Why does the King under the Mountain
fence himself in...
...like a robber in his hold?
THORIN: Perhaps it is because
I am expecting to be robbed.
BARD:
My lord...
...we have not come to rob you,
but to seek fair settlement.
Will you not speak with me?
[CAWING]
I am listening.
On behalf of the people of Lake-town
I ask that you honor your pledge.
A share of the treasure,
so that they might rebuild their lives.
I will not treat with any man...
...while an armed host lies before my door.
That armed host will attack this Mountain
if we do not come to terms.
And your threats do not sway me.
What of your conscience?
Does it not tell you our cause is just?
My people offered you help.
And in return, you brought upon them
only ruin and death.
When did Lake-town come to our aid
but for the promise of rich reward?
A bargain was struck!
A bargain?
What choice did we have
but to barter our birthright,
for blankets and food?
To ransom
our future in exchange
for our freedom?
You call that a fair trade?
Tell me...