GANDALF: Since when has my counsel
counted for so little?
What do you think I'm trying to do?
I think you're trying to save your Dwarvish
friends, and I admire your loyalty to them...
...but it does not dissuade me
from my course.
You started this, Mithrandir.
You will forgive me if I finish it.
Are the archers in position?
FEREN: Yes, my lord.
- Give the order.
If anything moves on that Mountain...
...kill it.
The Dwarves are out of time.
You, Bowman!
Do you agree with this?
Is gold so important to you?
Would you buy it
with the blood of Dwarves?
It will not come to that.
- This is a fight they cannot win.
BILBO: That won't stop them.
You think the Dwarves will surrender?
They won't.
They will fight to the
death to defend their own.
Bilbo Baggins.
THRANDUIL: If I'm not mistaken
this is the Halfling who stole the keys...
...to my dungeons from
under the nose of my guards.
Yes.
Sorry about that.
I came...
...to give you this.
The Heart of the Mountain.
The King's Jewel.
And worth a king's ransom.
How is this yours to give?
I took it as my 14th share
of the treasure.
BARD:
Why would you do this? You owe us no loyalty.
I'm not doing it for you.
I know that Dwarves can be obstinate...
...and pigheaded and...
...difficult.
They're suspicious and secretive...
...with the worst manners you can
possibly imagine, but they are also brave...
...and kind...
...and loyal to a fault.
I've grown very fond of them,
and I would save them if I can.
Now, Thorin values this stone above all else.
In exchange for its return,
I believe he will give you what you are owed.
There will be no need for war.
GANDALF: Rest up tonight.
You must leave on the morrow.
- Wha...?
Get as far away from here as possible.
- I--I'm not leaving.
You picked me as the 14th man. I'm
not about to leave the Company now.
- There is no Company. Not anymore.
And I don't like to think what Thorin will
do when he finds out what you've done.
- I'm not afraid of Thorin.
Well, you should be.
Don't underestimate the evil of gold.
Gold over which a serpent has long brooded.
Dragon-sickness seeps into the hearts
of all who come near this Mountain.
Almost all. Heh.