- Good morning.
What do you mean?
Do you wish me a good morning
or do you mean that it is a good morning...
...whether I want it or not'?
Or perhaps you mean to say that you feel good
on this particular morning?
Or are you simply stating
that this is a morning to be good on? Hm?
All of them at once, I suppose.
Hmm.
Can I help you?
That remains to be seen.
I'm looking for someone
to share in an adventure.
An adventure?
No, I don't imagine anyone west of Bree
would have much interest in adventures.
Nasty, disturbing, uncomfortable things.
Make you late for dinner. Heh, heh.
Mm.
Huh.
Hmm.
Oh. Ah.
Good morning.
To think that I should have lived
to be "good morninged"...
...by Belladonna Took's son
as if I were selling buttons at the door.
Beg your pardon?
You've changed,
and not entirely for the better...
...Bilbo Baggins.
I'm sorry, do I know you?
Well, you know my name,
although you don't remember I belong to it.
I'm Gandalf.
And Gandalf means...
...me.
Gandalf?
Not Gandalf the wandering Wizard...
...who made such excellent...
...fireworks? Old Took used to have them
on Midsummer's Eve. Heh, heh. Ahem.
No idea you were still in business.
And where else should I be?
Where else--? Ahem.
Well, I'm pleased to find you remember
something about me...
...even if it's only my fireworks.
Yes. Well, that's decided.
It'll be very good for you...
...and most amusing for me.
I shall inform the others.
Inform the who? What? No. No. No-- Wait.
We do not want...
...any adventures here,
Thank you. Not today. Not--
I suggest you try Over the Hill
or Across the Water.
Good morning.