Dwalin, at your service.
Hm. Uh...
Bilbo Baggins, at yours.
Do we...
...know each other?
No.
Which way, laddie?
Is it down here?
Is what...
...down where?
Supper.
He said there'd be food and lots of it.
He-- He said? Who said?
Mmm.
Very good, this. Any more?
What? Oh, yes, yes.
Ah.
Help yourself.
Hmm. It's just that, urn,
I wasn't expecting company.
That'll be the door.
Balin...
...at your service.
Good evening.
Yes. Yes, it is.
- Though I think it might rain later.
- Hm?
Am I late?
Late for what?
Oh!
Ha, ha!
Evening, brother.
By my beard...
...you're shorter and wider than last we met.
Wider, not shorter.
Sharp enough for both of us.
Uh, excuse me? Sorry, I hate to interrupt.
But the thing is, I'm not entirely sure
you're in the right house.
Have you eaten?
It's not that I don't like...
...visitors. I like visitors...
...as much as the next Hobbit.
But I do like to know them
before they come visiting.
- What is this?
- I don't know.
- I think it's cheese. Gone blue.
It's riddled with mold.
The thing is, I don't know either of you.
Not in the slightest. I don't mean...
...to be blunt, but I had to speak my mind.
- I'm sorry.
You think--?
Apology accepted.
- Ah.
Now, fill it up, brother...
...don't stint.
You wanna get stuck in?
- I could eat again if you insist, brother.
- Fili.
- And Kili.
At your service.
You must be Mr. Boggins.
Nope! You can't come in.
You've come to the wrong house.
What?
- Has it been canceled?
- No one told us.
No, nothing's been canceled.
That's a relief.
Careful with these.
I just had them sharpened.
-It's nice, this place.
Yeah.
- Did you do it yourself?
- What? No, it's been in the family for years.
That's my mother's glory box.
Can you please not do that?
Fili, Kili. Come on, give us a hand.
Mr. Dwalin. Ha, ha.
Shove this in the hallway.
Otherwise we'll never get everyone in.
"Everyone"? How many more are there?
Where do you want this?
- Oh, no.
It's really heavy.
No. No. There's nobody home!
Go away and bother somebody else.
There's far too many Dwarves
in my dining room as it is.
If this is some clot-head's idea of a joke...
...I can only say it is in very...
...poor taste.
Get off...
...you big lump!
Gandalf.