Put that back.
Not the jam please.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
It's a tad excessive, isn't it?
Have you got a cheese knife?
-"Cheese knife"? He eats it by the block.
Ugh.
No, that's Grandpa Mungo's chair--
No, so is that. Take it back, please.
- I cannot hear what you're saying.
It's an antique. Not for sitting on.
That is a book, not a coaster.
And put that map down.
- Excuse me, Mr. Gandalf?
- Yes?
May I tempt you with a cup of chamomile?
Oh, no, thank you, Dori.
A little red wine for me, I think.
Whoop! Mind out.
- Yes. Ah.
Uh, Fili, Kili. Uh...
Oin, Gloin.
Dwalin, Balin, Bifur, Bofur, Bombur...
-...Dori, Nori. Ori!
- No. Not my prizewinners, thank you.
No, thank you.
Yes, you're quite right, Bifur.
We appear to be one Dwarf short.
He is late, is all. He traveled north
to a meeting of our kin. He will come.
Mr. Gandalf? A little glass of red wine,
as requested.
It's got a fruity bouquet.
Oh. Cheers.
Bombur's on his second leg of lamb already.
Hmm.
No chance. Not from that distance.
Wanna bet? Bombur...
...catch!
I'll help you with that.
Oh, you great...
...galumphing git!
Who wants an ale? There you go.
Over here, brother.
I said have another...
...drink. Here you go.
Ale on the count of three!
One...
-...two...
- Up!
I knew you had it in you!
Excuse me, that is a doily, not a dishcloth.
But it's full of holes.
It's supposed to look like that. It's crochet.
And a wonderful game it is too,
if you've got the balls for it.
Bebother and confusticate these Dwarves!
My dear Bilbo, what on earth is the matter?
What's the matter?
I'm surrounded by Dwarves.
What are they doing here?
Oh, they're quite a merry gathering
once you get used to them.
I don't want to get used to them.
Look at the state of my kitchen.
There's mud trod into the carpet.
They've pillaged the pantry.
I won't tell you what they've done
in the bathroom.
They've destroyed the plumbing. I don't
understand what they're doing in my house!
Excuse me. I'm sorry to interrupt,
but what should I do with my plate?
Here you go, Ori. Give it to me.
Take that back.
Excuse me.
That's my mother's...
...West Farthing pottery. It's over...
...100 years old!
And can you...
...not do that?
You'll blunt them.
Ooh. Do you hear that, lads?
He says...
...we'll blunt the knives.
Blunt the knives, bend the forks
Smash the bottles and burn the corks
Chip the glasses and crack the plates
That's what Bilbo Baggins
Hates
Cut the cloth, tread on the fat
Leave the bones on the bedroom mat
Pour the milk on the pantry floor
Splash the wine
On every door
Dump the crooks in a boiling bowl
Pound them up with a thumping pole
When you're finished
If they are whole
Send them down the hall to roll
That's what Bilbo Baggins hates!
Bilbo.
He is here.
Gandalf.
I thought you said...
...this place would be easy...
...to find. I lost my way, twice.
I wouldn't have found it at all
had it not been for that mark on the door.
Mark? There's no mark on that door.
It was painted a week ago.
There is a mark. I put it there myself.
Bilbo Baggins, allow me to introduce
the leader of our company:
Thorin Oakenshield.
So...
...this is the Hobbit.
Tell me, Mr. Baggins,
have you done much fighting?
- Pardon me?
Axe or sword?
What's your weapon of choice?
Well, I do have some skill at conkers,
if you must know...
...but I fail to see why that's relevant.
Thought as much.
He looks more like a grocer than a burglar.
What news...
...from the meeting in Ered Luin?
Did they all come?
- Aye. Envoys from all seven kingdoms.
All of them!
DWALIN: And what did the Dwarves
of the Iron Hills say?
Is Dain with us?
They will not come.
They say this quest...
...is ours and ours alone.
You're going on a quest?
Bilbo, my dear fellow,
let us have a little more light.
Far to the east...
...over ranges and rivers...
...beyond woodlands and wastelands...
...lies a single, solitary peak.
"The Lonely Mountain."
Aye, Oin has read...
...the portents,
and the portents say it is time.
Ravens have been seen...
...flying back to the mountain,
as it was foretold.
"When the birds of yore return...
...to Erebor...
...the reign of the beast...
...will end."
- Uh, what beast?
That would be a reference...
...to Smaug the Terrible...
...chiefest and greatest...
...calamity of our age.
Airborne fire-breather.
Teeth like razors...
...claws like meat hooks.
Extremely fond of precious metals.
I know what a dragon is.
I'm not afraid. I'm up for it.
I'll give him a taste of Dwarfish iron
right up his jacksie!
Good lad, Ori!
Sit down.
The task would be difficult...
...with an army behind us...
...but we number just 13.
And not 13 of the best...
...nor brightest.
Here, who are you calling dim?
Sorry, what did he say?
We may be few in number...
...but we're fighters, all of us...
...to the last Dwarf.
And you forget,
we have a Wizard in our company.
Gandalf will have killed
hundreds of dragons.
Oh, well, no. I-- I wouldn't say--
How many, then?
- What?
How many dragons have you killed?
Go on.
Give us a number.
Excuse me. Please.
If we have read these signs...
...do you not think others
will have read them too?
Rumors have begun to spread.
The dragon, Smaug,
has not been seen for 60 years.
Eyes look east to the mountain, assessing...
...wondering, weighing the risk.
Perhaps the vast wealth of our people
now lies unprotected.
Do we sit back while others claim
what is rightfully ours?
Or do we seize this chance...
...to take back Erebor?
You forget, the Front Gate is sealed.
There is no way...
...into the mountain.
That, my dear Balin, is not entirely true.
How came you by this?
It was given to me...
...by your father.
By Thrain.
For safekeeping.
It is yours...
...now.
If there is a key...
...there must be a door.
These runes...
...speak of a hidden passage
to the Lower Halls.
There's another way in.
Well, if we can find it,
but Dwarf doors are invisible when closed.
The answer lies hidden somewhere
in this map...
...and I do not have the skill to find it.
But there are others in Middle-earth
who can.
The task I have in mind
will require a great deal of stealth...
...and no small amount of courage.
But if we are careful and clever,
I believe that it can be done.
That's why we need a burglar.
Hmm. And a good one too.
An expert, I'd imagine.
And are you?
Am I what?
He said he's an expert. Hey.
Me? No. No, no, no. I'm not a burglar.
I've never stolen a thing in my life.
Well, I'm afraid I have to agree
with Mr. Baggins.
He's hardly burglar material.
Nope.
Aye, the Wild is no place for gentle folk
who can neither fight nor fend for themselves.
He's just fine.
Enough!
If I say Bilbo Baggins...
...is a burglar, then a burglar...
...he is.
Hobbits are light...
...on their feet. In fact, they can pass
unseen by most, if they choose.
And, while the dragon is accustomed
to the smell of Dwarf...
...the scent of a Hobbit is all but...
...unknown to him,
which gives us a distinct advantage.
You asked me to find
the 14th member of this company...
...and I have chosen Mr. Baggins.
There's more to him...
...than appearances suggest.
And he's got a great deal more to offer
than any of you know.
Including himself.
You must trust me on this.
Very well.
- We will do it your way.
- No, no.
Give him the contract.
- We're in. We're off.
It's just the usual. Summary...
...of out-of-pocket expenses,
time required...
...remuneration...
...funeral arrangements, so forth.
Funeral arrangements?
I cannot guarantee his safety.
Understood.
Nor will I be responsible for his fate.
Agreed.
"Terms: Cash on...
...delivery, up to but not exceeding
one-fourteenth of total profit, if any."
Hmm. Seems fair.
"Present company shall not be liable
for injuries inflicted by...
...or sustained as a consequence thereof,
including, but not limited to lacerations...
...evisceration..."
-incineration?
Aye.
He'll melt the flesh off your bones
in the blink of an eye.
You all right, laddie?
Huh? Yeah.
Feel a bit faint.
- Think furnace with wings.
Air.
I need air.
Flash of light, searing pain, then:
Poof. You're nothing more than a pile of ash!
Hmm.
Nope.
Oh, very helpful, Bofur.
I'll be all right.
Just let me sit quietly for a moment.
You've been sitting quietly for far too long.
Tell me...
...when did doilies
and your mother's dishes...
...become so important to you?
I remember a young Hobbit who was always
running off in search of Elves in the woods.
Who would stay out late,
come home after dark...
...trailing mud and twigs and fireflies.
A young Hobbit who would have liked
nothing better...
...than to find out what was beyond
the borders of the Shire.
The world...
...is not in your books and maps.
It's out...
...there.
I can't just go running off into the blue.
I am a Baggins... of Bag-end.
You are also a Took.
Did you know...
...that your great-great-great-great-uncle...
...Bullroarer Took was so large...
...he could ride a real horse?
- Yes.
- Yes...
...well, he could.
In the Battle of Green Fields,
he charged the Goblin ranks.
He swung his club so hard,
it knocked the Goblin king's head clean off...
...and it sailed 100 yards through the air
and went down a rabbit hole.
And thus, the battle was won.
And the game of golf invented
at the same time.
I do believe you made that up.
Well, all good stories
deserve embellishment.
You'll have a tale or two to tell of your own
when you come back.
Can you promise that I will come back?
No.
And if you do...
...you will not be the same.
That's what I thought.
Sorry, Gandalf, I can't sign this.
You've got the wrong Hobbit.
It appears we have lost our burglar.
Probably for the best.
The odds were always against us.
After all, what are we?
Merchants, miners...
...tinkers, toy-makers.
Heh, heh. Hardly the stuff of legend.
There are a few warriors amongst us.
Old warriors.
I would take each and every one
of these Dwarves...
...over an army from the Iron Hills.
For when I called upon them,
they answered.
Loyalty, honor...
...a willing heart.
I can ask no more than that.
You don't...
...have to do this.
You have a choice.
You've done honorably by our people.
You have built a new life for us
in the Blue Mountains.
A life of peace...
...and plenty.
A life that is worth more than
all the gold in Erebor.
From my grandfather to my father,
this has come to me.
They dreamt of the day...
...when the Dwarves of Erebor
would reclaim their homeland.
There is no choice, Balin.
Not for me.
Then we are with you, laddie.
We will see it done.
Far over
HUMMINGThe misty mountains cold
To dungeons deep
And caverns old
We must away
'Ere break of day
To find our
Long-forgotten gold
The pines were roaring
On the height
The winds
Were moaning
In the night
The fire was red
It flaming spread
The trees like torches
Blazed With light