They could not have moved in daylight.
There must be a cave nearby.
Oh, what's that stench?
It's a Troll-hoard.
Be careful what you touch.
Seems a shame just to leave it...
...lying around.
- Anyone could take it.
- Agreed.
- Nori.
Yeah?
Get a shovel.
These swords were not made by any Troll.
Nor were they made
by any smith among Men.
These were forged in Gondolin...
...by the High Elves of the First Age.
You could not...
...wish for a finer blade.
Set it down.
That's good.
All right, come on. Quick.
We're making a long-term deposit.
Let's get out of this foul place.
Come on, let's go.
Bofur, Gloin, Nori.
Bilbo.
Hmm?
Here.
This is about your size.
I can't take this.
The blade is of Elvish make...
...which means...
...it will glow blue
when Orcs or Goblins are nearby.
I have never used a sword in my life.
And I hope you never have to.
But if you do, remember this:
True courage is about knowing
not when to take a life...
...but when to spare one.