The Valley of lmladris.
In the common tongue,
it's known by another name.
Rivendell.
Here lies the Last Homely House
East of the Sea.
This was your plan all along.
To seek refuge with our enemy.
You have no enemies here,
Thorin Oakenshield.
The only ill will to be found...
...in this valley
is that which you bring yourself.
You think the Elves will give our quest
their blessing?
They will try to stop us.
Of course they will. But we have questions
that need to be answered.
If we are to be successful,
this will need to be handled with tact.
And respect.
And no small degree of charm.
Which is why you will leave
the talking to me.
Mithrandir.
Ah.
Lindir.
Stay sharp.
I must speak with Lord Elrond.
My Lord Elrond is not here.
Not here?
Where is he?
Close ranks!
Gandalf.
Lord Elrond.