Our business is no concern of Elves.
For goodness sake, Thorin...
...show him the map.
It is the legacy...
...of my people.
It is mine to protect, as are its secrets.
Save me from the stubbornness
of Dwarves.
Your pride will be your downfall.
You stand in the presence
of one of the few in Middle-earth...
...who can read that map.
Show it to Lord Elrond.
Thorin, no.
Erebor.
What is your interest...
...in this map?
It's mainly academic.
As you know...
...this sort of artifact
sometimes contains hidden text.
You still read ancient Dwarvish,
do you not?
Moon runes?
Of course.
An easy thing to miss.
Well, in this case, that is true.
Moon runes can only be read
by the light of a moon...
...of the same shape and season...
...as the day on which they were written.
Can you read them?
These runes were written
on a Midsummer's Eve...
...by the light of a crescent moon
nearly 200 years ago.
It would seem you were meant
to come to Rivendell.
Fate is with you...
...Thorin Oakenshield. The same moon...
...shines upon us tonight.
"Stand by the...
...gray stone when the thrush knocks...
...and the setting sun with
the last light of Durin's Day...
-...will shine upon the keyhole."
- Durin's Day?
It is the start of the Dwarves' new year,
when the last moon of autumn...
...and the first sun of winter
appear in the sky together.
This is ill news.
Summer is passing.
Durin's Day will soon be upon us.
We still have time.
- Time? For what?
- To find the entrance.
We have to be standing in exactly
the right spot at exactly the right time.
Then, and only then,
can the door be opened.
So this is...
...your purpose, to enter the mountain?
What of it'?
There are some who would not deem it wise.
What do you mean?
You are not the only guardian
to stand watch over Middle-earth.