Where do you think...
---You're going?
Back to Rivendell.
No, no, you can't turn back now, eh?
You're part of the company.
You're one of us.
I'm not, though, am I?
Thorin said I should never have come
and he was right.
I'm not a Took...
...I'm a Baggins.
I don't know what I was thinking.
I should never have run out my door.
You're homesick. I understand.
No, you don't. You don't understand.
None of you do.
You're Dwarves.
You're used to this life.
To living on the road...
...never settling in one place,
not belonging anywhere!
Oh, I am sorry. I didn't--
No, you're right.
We don't belong anywhere.
I wish you all the luck in the world.
I really do.
What's that?
BI
Hmm?
Wake up!
Whoa!
Look out! Look out!
Get away!
Filthy scum!
Get back!
You'll pay for this!
Got you.
All right, all right.
Get off! Get your hands off me!
Get off me!