What's happening?
Keep moving.
Nori...
why have we stopped?
The path...
it's disappeared.
What's going on?
We've lost the path!
Find it.
All of you, look.
Look for the path!
I don't remember this bit.
None of it's familiar.
It's got to be here.
What hour is it?
I do not know. I do not
even know what day it is.
Is there no end
to this accursed forest?!
Attercop.
Look.
A tobacco pouch.
There's Dwarves in these woods.
Dwarves from the Blue
Mountains, no less.
This is exactly the same as mine.
Because it is yours.
Do you understand?
We're going around in circles.
We are lost.
We are not lost.
We keep heading east.
But which way is east?
We've lost the sun.
I thought you were the expert.
The sun.
We have to find...
the sun.
Up there.
We need to...
get above the canopy.
What was that?
Enough! Quiet! All of you!
We're being watched.
I can see a lake!
And a river.
And the Lonely Mountain.
We're almost there!
Can you hear me?
I know which way to go!
Hello?
Hello.
Oh, no.
Oh, come on.
Kill them! Kill them.
Eat them now, while
their blood is running.
Their hide is tough,
but there's good juice inside.
Stick it again.
Stick it again. Finish it off.
The meat's alive and kicking!
Kill him.
Kill him now.
Let us feast.
Feast! Feast!
Eat them alive!
Feast!
- What is it?
Eat them alive!
Fat and juicy.
Just a...
little taste.
Curse it! Where is it?!
Where is it?!
Here.
Ah! It stings!
It stings!
Sting.
That's a good name.
You all right there, Bofur?
- I'm all right!
- Get it off me!
Where's Bilbo?
I'm up here!