Galion, you old rogue,
we're running out of drink.
These empty barrels should have been
sent back to Esgaroth hours ago.
The bargeman will be waiting for them.
Say what you like about our...
ill-tempered king.
He has excellent taste in wine.
Come, Elros, try it.
I have the Dwarves...
...in my charge.
They're locked up. Where can they go?
Ha, ha.
I'll wager the sun is on the rise.
Must be nearly dawn.
We're never gonna reach
the mountain, are we?
Not stuck in here, you're not.
Bilbo!
What?
Shh! There are guards nearby!
- Ha, ha, ha.
- Close the doors.
- It'll buy us more time.
- All right, Nori.
- Up the stairs.
- You first.
Ori.
Not that way. Down here. Follow me.
Go.
Easy, now.
This way.