Watch out!
What are you trying...
to do, drown us?
I was born and bred on these waters,
Master Dwarf.
If I wanted to drown you...
I would not do it here.
I've had enough of this lippy Lakeman.
I say we throw him over the side
and be done with it.
- Bard, his name's Bard.
- How do you know?
I asked him.
I don't care what he calls himself.
I don't like him.
We do not have to like him.
We simply have to pay him.
Come on now, lads. Turn out...
your pockets.
How do we know he won't betray us?
We don't.
There's...
just a wee problem.
We're 10 coins short.
Gloin.
Come on.
- Give us what you have.
- Don't look to me.
I have been bled dry...
...by this venture.
What have I seen...
for my investment?
Naught but misery and...
...grief and...
Bless my beard.
Take it.
- Take all of it.
- Ahem.
The money, quick. Give it to me.
We will pay you when we...
get our provisions but not before.
If you value your freedom,
you'll do as I say.
There are guards ahead.
What's he doing?
He's talking to someone.
He's pointing right at us.
Now they're...
shaking hands.
- What?
- The villain.
He's selling us out.
Quiet.
We're approaching the tollgate.
Halt!
Goods inspection!
Papers, please!
It's you, Bard.
Morning, Percy.
Anything to declare?
Nothing, but that I am cold and tired...
and ready for home.
You and me both.
There we are.
All in order.