You all right?
I can manage.
Let's just get out of here.
Run!
Quickly! Move now!
Get off me! Get off!
Move them along here.
Move on!
What is the meaning of this?
We caught them stealing weapons, sire.
Enemies of the state?
A desperate bunch of...
mercenaries, if ever there was, sire.
Hold your tongue!
You do not know to whom you speak.
This is no common criminal.
This is Thorin...
son of Thrain, son of Thror!
We are the Dwarves of Erebor.
We have come to reclaim our homeland.
I remember this town
in the great days of old.
Fleets of boats lay at harbor...
filled with silks and fine gems.
This was no forsaken town on a lake.
This was the center of all trade
in the North!
I would...
see those days return.
I would relight the great forges
of the Dwarves...
and send wealth and riches...
flowing once more
from the Halls of Erebor!
Death!
That is what you will...
...bring upon us!
Dragon fire and ruin.
If you waken that beast...
it will destroy us all.
You can listen to this naysayer...
but I promise you this:
If we succeed...
all will share in the wealth
of the mountain.
You will have enough gold
to rebuild Esgaroth...
10 times over!