All of you!
Listen to me!
You must listen!
Have you forgotten
what happened to Dale?
Have you forgotten those...
who died in the firestorm?!
And for what purpose?
The blind ambition of a Mountain King...
so riven by greed, he could not...
see beyond his own desire!
Now, now!
We must not, any of us...
be too quick to lay blame.
Let us... not
forget that it was...
Girion, Lord of Dale...
your ancestor...
who failed to kill the beast!
It's true, sire.
We all know the story.
Arrow after arrow, he shot.
Each one missing its mark.
You have no right.
No right to enter that mountain.
I have the only right.
I speak to the Master...
of the Men of the Lake.
Will you see the prophecy fulfilled?
Will you...
share in the great wealth
of our people?
What say you?
I say unto you...
Welcome!
And thrice...
welcome... King
Under the Mountain!