I will put the next one between your eyes.
We have come to tell you...
...payment of your debt has been offered...
...and accepted.
What payment?
I gave you nothing.
You have nothing.
We have this.
They have the Arkenstone.
Thieves!
How came you by the heirloom
of our house?
That stone belongs to the king!
And the king may have it...
...with our goodwill.
But first he must honor his word.
They are taking us for fools.
This is a ruse.
A filthy lie.
The Arkenstone is in this Mountain!
It is a trick!
It's no trick.
The stone is real.
I gave it to them.
You?
I took it as my 14th share.
You would steal from me?
Steal from you? No.
No, I may be a burglar,
but I like to think I'm an honest one.
I'll let it stand against my claim.
Against your claim?
Your claim.
You have no claim over me,
you miserable rat!
I was going to give it to you.
- Many times I wanted to, but...
- But what...
...thief?
You are changed, Thorin.
The Dwarf I met...
...in Bag End would never have
gone back on his word.
Would never have doubted...
...the loyalty of his kin!
Do not speak to me...
...of loyalty.
Throw him from the rampart!
Did you not hear me?
I will do it myself. Curse you!
No!
Cursed be the Wizard...
- ...that forced you on us!
- If you don't like my burglar...
...then please...
...don't damage him.
Return him to me.
You're not making a very splendid figure
as King under the Mountain...
...are you, Thorin...
...son of Thrain?
Never again will I have dealings
with Wizards!
Go.
Or Shire rats!
Are we resolved?
The return...
...of the Arkenstone
for what was promised?