Since when do we forsake...
...our own people?
Thorin...
...they are dying...
...out there.
There are halls beneath halls
within this Mountain.
Places we can fortify...
...shore up, make safe.
Yes.
Yes...
...that is it.
We must move the gold
further underground...
- ...to safety.
- Did you hear me?
Dain is surrounded.
They're being slaughtered, Thorin.
Many die in war.
Life is cheap.
But a treasure...
...such as this cannot be counted...
...in lives lost.
It is worth...
...all the blood we can spend.
You sit here in these vast halls...
...with a crown upon your head...
...and yet you are lesser now
than you have ever been.
Do not speak to me...
...as if I were some lowly Dwarf Lord...
...as if...
...I were still...
...Thorin...
...Oakenshield.
- I am your king!
- You were always my king.
You used to know that once.
You cannot see what you have become.
Go.
Get out.
Before I kill you.
You sit here...
...with a crown upon your head.
You are lesser now
than you have ever been.
But a treasure such as this
cannot be counted in lives lost.
A sickness lies upon that treasure.
The blind ambition of a Mountain King.
Am I not the king?
This gold...
...is ours.
And ours alone.
I will not part...
...with a single coin.
He could not see
beyond his own desire!
As if I were some lowly Dwarf Lord...
...Thorin Oakenshield.
A sickness which drove
your grandfather mad.
This is Thorin...
...son of Thrain, son of Thror!
I am not my grandfather.
You are the heir to the Throne of Durin.
They are dying out there.
Take back Erebor.
Dain is surrounded.
Dying.
Is surrounded.
Take back your homeland.
You are changed, Thorin.
I am not my grandfather.
Is this treasure truly worth more
than your honor?
I am not my grandfather.