The Valley of Imladris.
ln the common tongue,
it's known by another name.
Rivendell.
GANDALF: Here lies the Last
Homely House East of the Sea.
This was your plan all along.
To seek refuge with our enemy.
You have no enemies here,
Thorin Oakenshield.
The only ill will to be found in this
valley is that which you bring yourself.
You think the Elves will
give our quest their blessing?
They will try to stop us.
Of course they will. But we have
questions that need to be answered.
If we are to be successful,
this will need to be handled with tact.
And respect.
And no small degree of charm.
Which is why you will
leave the talking to me.
LINDIR:
Mithrandir.
Ah. Lindir.
Stay sharp.
[IN ELVISH]
I must speak with Lord Elrond.
[IN ENGLISH]
My Lord Elrond is not here.
Not here?
Where is he?
[HORN SOUNDS]
[THORIN SHOUTS IN DWARVISH]
THORIN:
Close ranks!
-Gandalf.
-Lord Elrond.
[IN ELVISH]