Too many boneses, precious.
Not enough flesh!
Shut up! Cut its skin off.
Start with its head.
[GOLLUM GROANING]
[SINGING] The cold hard lands
They bites our hands
They gnaws our feet
The rocks and stones
They're like old bones
All bare of meat
Cold as death
Without no breath
It's good to eat
[GOBLIN SCREAMS]
Bless us and splash us, precious.
That's a meaty mouthful.
Gollum, gollum! Aah.
Back. Stay back.
I'm warning you, don't come any closer.
It's got an Elfish blade.
But it's not an Elfs.
Not an Elfs, no.
What is it, precious?
What is it?
My name is Bilbo Baggins.
Bagginses?
What is a Bagginses, precious?
-I'm a Hobbit from the Shire.
-Oh.
We like Goblinses, batses and fishes.
But we hasn't tried Hobbitses before.
ls it soft? ls it juicy?
Now, now, keep your distance!
I'll use this if I have to.
Aah!
I don't want any trouble,
do you understand?
Just show me the way to get out of here
and I'll be on my way.
Why? ls it lost?
Yes. Yes, and I want to get unlost
as soon as possible.
Ooh, we knows!
We knows safe paths for Hobbitses.
Safe paths in the dark.
Shut up!
-I didn't say anything.
-We wasn't talking to you.
Oh, yes, we was, precious. We was.
Look, I don't know what your game is,
but I--
Games?!
Oh, we love games,
doesn't we, precious?
Does it like games? Does it, does it?
Does it like to play?
Maybe.
What has roots as nobody sees?
ls taller than trees?
Up, up, up it goes
And yet, never grows
-The mountain.
-Yes, yes.
Oh, let's have another one, eh?
Yes! Do it again, do it again. Ask us.
No! No more riddles.
Finish him off. Finish him now!
Gollum, gollum!
No! No. No.
No. I want to play. I do.
I want to play. I can see...
...you are very good at this.
So why don't we...
...have a game of riddles? Yes?
Just--Just you and me.
Yes. Yes, just us.
Yes. Yes.
And if I win...
...you show me the way out. Yes?
Yes. Yes.
And if it loses? What then?
Well, if it loses, precious,
then we eats it!
If Baggins loses, we eats it whole.
Fair enough.
Well, Baggins first.
Thirty white horses on a red hill
First they champ, then they stamp
Then they stand still
Teeth?
Teeth! Oh, yes, my precious!
But we-- We only have nine.
Our turn.
Voiceless, it cries
Wingless flutters
Toothless bites
Mouthless mutters
Just a minute. Uh....
Oh. Oh!
We knows! We knows!
Shut up!
Wind.
It's wind. Of course it is.
Very clever, Hobbitses.
Very clever.
Ah-ah-ah.
A box without hinges, key or lid
Yet golden treasure inside is hid
Box.
Oh, um....
Box. The lid and a key.
-Well?
-It's nasty.
-Box. Key.
-Do you give up?
Give us a chance, precious!
Give us a chance!
[GRUNTING]
Eggses!
Wet, crunchy little eggses. Yes.
Grandmother taught us
to suck them, yes!
[WINGS FLUTTERING]
[GOLLUM EXHALES]
GOLLUM:
We have one for you.
All things it devours
Birds, beasts, trees, flowers
Gnaws iron, bites steel
Grinds hard stones to meal
Answer us.
Give me a moment, please.
I gave you a good long while.
Birds, beasts.... Beasts?
Trees, flowers.
I don't know this one.
GOLLUM:
ls it tasty?
ls it scrumptious?
ls it crunchable?
Let me think.
It's stuck.
Bagginses is stuck.
Time's up.
Time.
The answer is time.
[GROWLING]
Actually it wasn't that hard.
Last question.
Last chance.
BILBO:
Okay.
Ask us.
-Ask us!
-Yes, yes. All right.
What have I got in my pocket?
That's no fair.
It's not fair! It's against the rules!
Now ask us another one.
No. No, no, no.
You said ask me a question.
Well, that is my question.
What have I got in my pocket?
[GROANS]
Three guesses, precious.
lt must give us three!
Three guesses. Very well, guess away.
Handses!
Wrong. Guess again.
[GRUNTS]
Fishbones, Goblins' teeth,
wet shells, bats' wings....
[GRUNTING]
Knife! Oh, shut up!
Wrong again. Last guess.
String. Or nothing.
Two guesses at once.
Wrong both times.
[SOBBING]
BILBO:
So....
Come, then. I won the game.
You promised to show me the way out.
GOLLUM:
Did we say so, precious?
Did we say so?
What has it got in its pocketses?
That's no concern of yours.
You lost.
Lost? Heh...
Lost.
Lost...
Where is it?
Where is it?!
No!
[SCREAMS]
Where is it?!
No! No!
Lost!
Curse us and splash us!
My precious is lost!
-What have you lost?
-Mustn't ask us! Not its business!
No!
Gollum, gollum!
[PANTING]
What has it got...
...in its nasty, little pocketses?
He stole it.
He stole it!
[SCREAMS]