Ah, Bilbo.
There you are.
Now, this will require some delicate handling.
We must tread very carefully.
The last person to have startled him
was torn to shreds.
I will go first and uh, Bilbo?
You come with me.
- Is this a good idea?
GANDALF: Yes.
Now, the rest of you, you just wait here...
...and don't come out until I give the signal.
BOFUR: Right.
Wait for the signal.
And no sudden moves or loud noises,
and don't overcrowd him.
And only come out in pairs. Right.
No, actually, Bombur...
...um, you count as two
so you should come out alone.
Mm.
Remember, wait for the signal.
BOFUR: The signal. Right.
What signal would that be?
GANDALF: Ahem.
- You're nervous.
Nervous? What nonsense.
Good morning.
Good morning!
BEORN: Who are you?
I'm Gandalf. Gandalf the Grey.
Never heard of him.
I'm a Wizard.
Perhaps you've heard of my colleague
Radagast the Brown.
He resides in the southern borders
of Mirkwood.
What do you want?
Well, simply to thank you
for your hospitality.
You may have noticed that we took refuge...
...in your lodgings here last night.
Who is this little fellow?
Well, this would be Mr. Baggins...
...from the Shire.
He's not a Dwarf, is he?
Why, no. No, he's a Hobbit.
A good family
and unimpeachable reputation.
A Halfling and a Wizard.
How come you here?
GANDALF: Oh, well, the fact is
that we've had a bad time of it...
...from Goblins in the mountains.
What did you go near Goblins for?
Stupid thing to do.
You are absolutely right...
- There it is. Go. Go.
GANDALF: It was terrible.
DWALIN: Dwalin, and Balin.
GANDALF: And I, uh, I must confess that,  uh...
...several of our group are, in fact, Dwarves.
Do you call two...
"several"?
Well, uh, now you put it that way...
(STUTTERING)
Yes, there could be more than two.
BOFUR: Go, go.
GLOIN: Wait, that's us.
GANDALF: Oh, and here are some more
of our, uh, happy troop.
And do you call six a "troop"?
(LAUGHS)
What are you, a traveling circus?
BOFUR: Go.
Go. Go, go.
Dori and Ori at your service.
BEORN: I don't
want your service.
Absolutely understandable.
Go. Go.
Oh, Fili and Kili. I'd quite forgotten. Yes.
Oh, yes, and uh, Nori, Bofur,
Bifur...
...and Bombur.
Is that it?
Are there any more?
Ah.
So you are the one they call Oakenshield.