ELROS: Galion, you old rogue,
we're running out of drink.
These empty barrels should have been
sent back to Esgaroth hours ago.
The bargeman will be waiting for them.
GALION:
Say what you like about our...
...ill-tempered king.
He has excellent taste in wine.
Come, Elros, try it.
ELROS:
I have the Dwarves...
...in my charge.
GALION:
They're locked up. Where can they go? Ha, ha.
BOFUR:
I'll wager the sun is on the rise.
Must be nearly dawn.
We're never gonna reach
the mountain, are we?
Not stuck in here, you're not.
Bilbo!
KILI:
What?
[DWARVES CHATTER]
Shh! There are guards nearby!
- Ha, ha, ha.
THORIN: Close the doors.
- It'll buy us more time.
- All right, Nori.
THORIN: Up the stairs.
DWALIN: You first.
Ori.
BILBO:
Not that way. Down here. Follow me.
Go.
OIN:
Easy, now.
[SNORING]
[WHISPERING]
This way.