Watch out!
What are you trying to do, drown us?
I was born and bred on these waters,
Master Dwarf.
If I wanted to drown you...
...I would not do it here.
Oh, I've had enough of this lippy Lakeman.
I say we throw him over the side
and be done with it.
- Bard, his name's Bard.
BOFUR: How do you know?
Uh, I asked him.
I don't care what he calls himself.
I don't like him.
BALIN:
We do not have to like him.
We simply have to pay him.
Come on now, lads.
Turn out your pockets.
How do we know he won't betray us?
We don't.
BALIN:
There's um... just a wee problem.
We're 10 coins short.
Gloin.
- Come on. Give us what you have.
- Don't look to me.
I have been bled dry by this venture.
What have I seen for my investment?
Naught but misery and grief and--
GLOIN:
Bless my beard.
Take it.
- Take all of it.
- Ahem.
The money, quick. Give it to me.
THORIN: We will pay you when
we get our provisions but not before.
If you value your freedom,
you'll do as I say.
There are guards ahead.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
What's he doing?
BILBO:
He's talking to someone.
He's pointing right at us.
Now they're shaking hands.
- What?
DWALIN:
The villain. He's selling us out.
[CLANKING]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[GRUNTING]
[DWARVES GRUNTING]
BARD:
Quiet.
We're approaching the tollgate.
PERCY:
Halt!
Goods inspection!
Papers, please!
Oh, it's you, Bard.
Morning, Percy.
Anything to declare?
Nothing, but that I am cold and tired...
...and ready for home.
You and me both.
There we are.
All in order.