Da! Where have you been?
Father! There you are! I was worried.
Here, Sigrid.
Bain, get them in.
If you speak of this to anyone...
...I'll rip your arms off.
Get off.
Up there.
SIGRID:
Da...
...why are there Dwarves
climbing out of our toilet?
Will they bring us luck?
They may not be the best fit...
...but they'll keep you warm.
Thank you very much.
A Dwarvish windlance.
BILBO:
You look like...
...you've seen a ghost.
He has.
The last time we saw...
...such a weapon...
...a city was on fire.
It was the day the dragon came.
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
The day that Smaug...
...destroyed Dale.
Girion, the Lord of the City...
...rallied his bowmen...
...to fire upon the beast.
But a dragon's hide is tough.
Tougher than the strongest armor.
Only a Black Arrow fired from a windlance...
...could have pierced the dragon's hide.
And few of those...
...arrows were ever made.
The store was running low...
...when Girion...
...made his last stand.
Had the aim of Men been true that day...
...much would have been different.
You speak as if you were there.
All Dwarves know the tale.
Then you would know
that Girion hit the dragon.
He loosened a scale under the left wing.
One more shot and
he would have killed the beast.
[DWALIN CHUCKLES]
That's a fairy story, lad.
Nothing more.
You took our money.
Where are the weapons?