THORIN:
Anything?
DWALIN:
Nothing!
THORIN:
If the map is true...
...then the hidden door
lies directly above us.
BILBO:
Up here!
You have keen eyes, Master Baggins.
[GRUNTING]
[PANTS]
THORIN:
This must be it.
The hidden door.
THORIN: Let all those who doubted us...
...rue this day!
[ALL CHEERING]
Right, then. We have a key.
Which means that somewhere...
...there is a key-hole.
THORIN:
"The last light of Durin's Day...
...will shine upon the key-hole."
Nori.
[DWALIN GRUNTING]
We're losing the light. Come on.
NORI:
Be quiet! I can't hear when you're thumping.
I can't find it.
It's not here!
It's not! Here!
THORIN: Break it down!
DWALIN: Aye.
Come on!
DWALIN:
Break!
It has to break.
BALIN:
It's no good.
The door's sealed. Can't be opened by force.
There's a powerful magic on it.
No!
"The last light of Durin's Day...
...will shine upon the key-hole."
That is what it says.
What did we miss?
Balin?
We've lost the light.
There's no more to be done.
We had but one chance.
Come away, lads.
It's over.
- Wait a minute.
GLOIN: We're too late.
BILBO:
Where are they going?
You can't give up now!
Thorin.
You can't give up now.
"Stand by the gray stone...
...when the thrush knocks."
The setting sun.
And "the last light of Durin's Day
will shine..."
The last light.
Last light.
[CLICKING ON STONE]
The last light!
The key-hole!
Come back!
It's the light of the moon!
The last moon of autumn!
Ha, ha, ha!
Where's the key? Where's the key?
Where's the--?
It was here.
Come on, it was-- It was here.
It was just--
[TINKLING]
[THUMP]
Erebor.
Thorin.
I know these walls.
These halls.
This stone.
You remember it, Balin.
Chambers filled with golden light.
I remember.
"Herein lies the Seventh
Kingdom of Durin's Folk.
May the Heart of the Mountain
unite all Dwarves...
...in defense of this home."
The Throne of the King.
- Ah.
And what's that above it?
The Arkenstone.
Arkenstone.
And what's that?
That, Master Burglar...
...is why you are here.