(WHISPERING) Hello?
(KNOCKS ECHOING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
He's not at home.
Not at home. Ahem.
Good.
Good, good, good.
What's that?
Shush. Shush.
Arkenstone.
A large, white jewel.
Very helpful.
(SMAUG EXHALES)
(SNIFFING)
Well...
...thief.
I smell you.
I hear your breath.
I feel...
...your air.
Where are you?
Come, now...
...don't be shy.
Step into the light.
Hmm.
There is something about you.
Something you...
...carry.
Something made of gold.
But far more...
...precious.
VOICE OF THE RING: Precious! Precious!
There you are...
...Thief in the...
...Shadows.
I did not come to steal from you...
...O Smaug...
...the Unassessably Wealthy.
I merely wanted...
...to gaze upon your magnificence.
To see...
...if you really were as great
as the old tales say.
I did not believe them.
And do you now?!
Truly...
...the tales and songs...
...fall utterly short of your enormity...
...O Smaug the Stupendous.
Do you think flattery will keep you alive?
No, no.
No, indeed.
You seem familiar with my name...
...but I don't remember smelling
your kind before.
Who are you...
...and where do you come from...
...may I ask?
I come from under the hill.
Underhill?
BILBO: And under hills...
...and over hills my path has led.
And... And...
...through the air.
I am he who walks unseen.
Impressive.
What else do you claim to be?
I am...
Luck-wearer.
Riddle-maker.
Lovely titles.
Go on.
Barrel-rider.
Barrels? Now that is interesting.
And what about...
...your little Dwarf friends?
Where are they hiding?
Dwarves?
No.
No, no. No Dwarves here.
You've got that all wrong.
Oh, I don't think so, Barrel-rider!
They sent you in here...
...to do their dirty work while they...
...skulk about outside.
Truly...
...you are mistaken...
...O Smaug, Chiefest
and Greatest of Calamities.
You have nice manners...
...for a thief and...
...a liar!
I know the smell and taste of Dwarf.
No one better!
It is the gold!
They are drawn...
...to treasure like...
...flies to dead flesh.
Did you think I did not know...
...this day would come?!
That a pack of...
...canting Dwarves...
...would come crawling back...
...to the mountain?!