THORIN:
It is here in these halls.
I know it.
DWALIN:
We have searched and searched.
THORIN:
Not well enough.
DWALIN:
Thorin, we all would see the stone returned.
THORIN:
And yet, it is still not found!
Do you doubt the loyalty of anyone here?
The Arkenstone...
...is the birthright of our people.
It is The King's Jewel.
Am I not the king?
Know this:
If anyone should find it...
...and withhold it from me...
...I will be avenged.
[SIGHING]
Dragon-sickness.
I've seen it before.
That look.
The terrible need.
It is a fierce and jealous love, Bilbo.
It sent his grandfather mad.
Balin, if Thorin...
...had the Arkenstone...
...or if...
...it was found...
...would it help?
That stone crowns all.
It is the summit of this great wealth...
...bestowing power...
...upon he who bears it.
Would it stay his madness?
No, laddie.
I fear it would make him worse.
Perhaps it is best...
...it remains lost.
THORIN:
What is that?
In your hand.
It's nothing.
Show me.
It...
I picked it up in Beorn's garden.
You've carried it all this way?
I'm gonna plant it in my garden.
In Bag End.
It's a poor prize to take back to the Shire.
One day, it'll grow.
And every time I look at it, I'll remember.
Remember everything that happened,
the good, the bad...
...and how lucky I am that I made it home.
Thorin, I...
DWALIN:
Thorin.
Survivors from Lake-town...
...they're streaming into Dale.
There's hundreds of them.
Call everyone to the gate.
To the gate!
Now!
[CHATTERING]
BARD: Come on. Keep moving.