...why should I honor such terms?
Because you gave us your word.
Does that mean nothing?
Be gone!
Ere our arrows...
...fly!
[GRUNTS]
BILBO:
What are you doing?
You cannot go to war.
- This does not concern you.
- Excuse me...
...but in case you haven't noticed,
there is an army of Elves out there.
Not to mention several hundred
angry fishermen.
We are, in fact, outnumbered.
Not for much longer.
What does that mean?
It means, Master Baggins...
...you should never underestimate Dwarves.
We have reclaimed Erebor.
Now...
...we defend it.
He will give us nothing.
Such a pity.
Still...
- ...you tried.
- I do not understand.
Why?
Why would he risk war?
[GRUNTING]
It is fruitless to reason with them.
They understand...
...only one thing.
We attack at dawn.
Are you with us?
Aye.
THORIN:
Master Baggins, come here.
You're going to need this.
Put it on.
This vest is made of silver steel.
Mithril...
...it was called by my forebears.
No blade can pierce it.
I look absurd.
I'm not a warrior, I'm a Hobbit.
It is a gift.
A token of our friendship.
True friends are hard to come by.
I have been blind...
...but now I begin to see.
I am betrayed.
Betrayed?
The Arkenstone.
One of them has taken it.
One of them is false.
Thorin...
...the Quest is fulfilled,
you've won the Mountain.
Is that not enough?
- Betrayed by my own kin.
- Now, uh...
...you made a promise
to the people of Lake-town.
Now, is this treasure...
...truly worth more than your honor?
Our honor, Thorin. I was also there.
I gave my word.
For that, I am grateful.
It was nobly done, but the treasure...
...does not belong to the people...
...of Lake-town.
This gold...
...is ours.
And ours alone.
By my life...
...I will not part...
...with a single coin.
Not...
...one...
...piece of it.