GANDALF: Since when has my counsel
counted for so little?
What do you think I'm trying to do?
Save your Dwarvish friends,
and I admire...
...your loyalty to them.
But it does not dissuade me
from my course.
You started this, Mithrandir.
You will forgive me if I finish it.
Are the archers in position?
FEREN: Yes, my lord.
- Give the order.
If anything moves on that Mountain...
...kill it.
The Dwarves are out of time.
You, Bowman!
Do you agree?
Is gold so important to you?
Would you buy it
with the blood of Dwarves?
It won't come to that.
- This is a fight they cannot win.
BILBO: That won't stop them.
You think the Dwarves will surrender?
They won't.
They will fight to the death.
Bilbo Baggins.
THRANDUIL:
If I'm not mistaken...
...this is the Halfling who stole the keys...
...to my dungeons from under...
...the nose of my guards.
Yes.
Sorry...
...about that.
I came...
...to give you...
...this.
The Heart of the Mountain.
The King's Jewel.
And worth a king's ransom.
How is this...
...yours to give?
I took it as my 14th share
of the treasure.
BARD:
Why would you do this?
You owe us no loyalty.
I'm not doing it for you.
I know that Dwarves can be obstinate...
...and pigheaded...
...and difficult.
They're suspicious and secretive...
...with the worst manners...
...imaginable,
but they are also brave...
...and kind...
...and loyal to a fault.
I've grown...
...very fond of them,
and I would save them if I can.
Now, Thorin...
...values this stone above all else.
In exchange for its return,
he will give you...
...what you are owed.
There will be no need...
...for war.
GANDALF:
Rest up tonight.
- You must leave on the morrow.
- What?
- Get as far away from here as possible.
- I'm not leaving.
You picked me as the 14th man.
I'm not leaving the Company.
There is no Company. Not anymore.
Imagine what Thorin will do
when he finds out what you've done.
I'm not afraid of Thorin.
Well, you should be.
Don't underestimate...
...the evil of gold.
Gold over which...
...a serpent has long brooded.
Dragon-sickness seeps
into the hearts of all...
...who come near this Mountain.
Almost all. Heh.