Ironfoot.
[SHOUTING]
[ALL SHOUTING]
[SHOUTS IN ELVISH]
DAIN:
Hey, Thorin!
Ironfoot has come!
Who is that?
He doesn't look very happy.
It is Dain, Lord of the Iron Hills.
Thorin's...
- ...cousin.
- Are they alike?
I've always found Thorin
the more reasonable of the two.
DAIN:
Good morning.
How are we all?
I have a wee proposition...
...if you wouldn't mind giving me
a few moments...
...of your time.
Would you consider...
...just sodding off?
All of you!
Right now!
Stand fast.
Come now, Lord Dain.
Gandalf the Grey.
Tell this rabble...
...to leave, or I'll water...
...the ground with their blood!
No need for war...
...between Dwarves, Men and Elves.
A legion of Orcs...
...march on the Mountain.
Stand down.
I will not stand down before any Elf.
Not least this faithless Woodland sprite.
He wishes nothing but ill upon my people.
If he chooses...
...to stand between me and my kin...
...I'll split his pretty head open!
See if he's still smirking then.
Dain...
...wait!
[ALL SHOUTING]
Let them advance.
See how far they get.
DAIN: You think I give a dead dog
for your threats...
...you pointy-eared...
...princess?
You hear that, lads? We're on!
Let's give these bastards
a good hammering!
[SHOUTING IN DWARVISH]
[ALL SHOUTING]
Stand your men down.
I'll deal with Ironfoot and his rabble.
Right then.
Let's get this done.
Send in the goats.
[DWARF SHOUTS IN DWARVISH]
[SHOUTING IN ELVISH]