[SQUAWKING]
The Eagles are coming.
[COUGHING AND GASPING]
Bilbo.
Don't move. Don't move. Lie still.
Oh. Mm. Mm.
I'm glad you are here.
- Shh, shh.
- Unh.
I wish to part from you in friendship.
No.
You are not going anywhere, Thorin.
You're going to live.
I would take back...
...my words and my deeds at the Gate.
You did what only a true friend would do.
Forgive me.
I was too blind to see it.
I am so sorry...
...that I have led you into such peril.
No, I'm glad to have shared
in your perils, Thorin.
Each and every one of them.
It is far more than any Baggins deserves.
Farewell...
...Master Burglar.
Go back to your books.
And your armchair.
Plant your trees.
Watch them grow.
[GROANS]
If more people...
...valued home...
...above gold...
...this world would be a merrier place.
[GRUNTS]
No. No, no, no. No.
Thorin. Thorin, don't you dare.
Thorin.
Thorin. Thorin, hold on.
Hold on, please.
The Eagles...
The Eagles... The Eagles are here.
Thorin?
The Ea...
[SOBBING]