BALIN:
There is to be a great feast tonight.
Songs will be sung. Tales will be told.
And Thorin Oakenshield...
...will pass into legend.
I know that's how you must honor him.
But to me, he was never that.
He was...
To me...
...he was...
I'll slip quietly away.
Will you tell the others I said goodbye?
You can tell them yourself.
If any of you are ever passing Bag End, uh...
...tea is at 4.
There's plenty of it.
You are welcome anytime.
Uh...
Don't bother knocking.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
[GANDALF CHUCKLES]
GANDALF:
Ah, the borders of the Shire.
It is here I must leave you.
That's a shame.
I quite liked having...
...a Wizard around.
Seems they bring good luck.
You don't really suppose, do you,
that all your adventures and escapes...
...were managed by mere luck?
Magic rings should not be used lightly,
Bilbo.
Don't take me for a fool.
I know you found one in the Goblin tunnels.
And I've kept my eye on you...
...ever since.
Well, thank goodness.
Farewell, Gandalf.
Farewell.
You, uh...
You needn't worry about that ring.
Fell out of my pocket during the battle.
I lost it.
You're a very fine person, Mr. Baggins.
And I'm very fond...
...of you.
But you're only quite a little fellow...
...in a wide world after all.
[HOBBITS CHATTERING]
Wait a minute,
that's my mother's glory box.
And that's my dining chair.
Ah... Put that pouf down!
What is going on?
WORRYWORT:
Hello...
...Mr. Bilbo.
You're not supposed to be here.
What do you mean?
On account of you
being presumed dead.
I am not dead.
Presumed or otherwise.
WORRYWORT:
I'm not sure that's permitted.
Mr. Bilbo!
TOSSER:
Twenty-one! Any advance on 21?
Any advance on 21?
Ha, ha! Sold to Mrs. Bolger.
Somewhere for Fatty to put his feet on.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Any bids for this?
This is Shire-made.
No Dwarvish reproductions here.
BILBO:
Stop!
- There's been a mistake!
LOBELIA: Who are you?
Who am I?
You know who I am...
...Lobelia Sackville-Baggins.
This is my home.
And those are my spoons.
Thank you very much.
TOSSER: This is most irregular.
- Excuse me.
TOSSER:
It's been more...
...than 13 months since the disappearance.
If you are in fact...
...Bilbo Baggins and undeceased...
...can you prove it?
What?
Something official with your name...
...on it would suffice.
All right. Right.
[CROWD MURMURING]
A contract of employment as a bur...
Never mind as what.
There. My signature.
Yes, well... Uh...
Well, it certainly seems to be in order.
Yes.
Seems there can be no doubt.
Who is this you pledged
your service to?
Thorin Oakenshield?
He...
He was my friend.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
No, thank you!
We don't want any more visitors,
well-wishers...
...or distant relations!
GANDALF:
And what about...
...very old friends?
BILBO:
Gandalf?
GANDALF:
Bilbo Baggins.
BILBO:
My dear Gandalf! Ha, ha!
GANDALF:
It's good to see you.
One hundred and 11 years old.
Who would believe it?
[BOTH LAUGHING]
BILBO:
Come on, come in!
Welcome. Welcome.