In those days, I was always on time.
I was entirely respectable.
And nothing unexpected...
...ever happened.
[GASPS]
- Good morning.
GANDALF: What do you mean?
Do you mean to wish
me a good morning...
...or do you mean that it is a good
morning whether I want it or not?
Or perhaps you mean to say that you
feel good on this particular morning?
Or are you simply stating
that this is a morning to be good on? Hm?
All of them at once, I suppose.
GANDALF:
Hmm.
Can I help you?
That remains to be seen.
I'm looking for someone
to share in an adventure.
An adventure?
No, I don't imagine anyone west of Bree
would have much interest in adventures.
Nasty, disturbing, uncomfortable things.
Make you late for dinner. Heh, heh.
Mm. Huh.
Hmm.
Oh. Ah. Good morning.
To think that I should have lived
to be "good morninged"...
...by Belladonna Took's son as if
I were selling buttons at the door.
Beg your pardon?
You've changed, and not entirely
for the better, Bilbo Baggins.
I'm sorry, do I know you?
Well, you know my name, although you
don't remember I belong to it. I'm Gandalf.
And Gandalf means...
...me.
Gandalf?
Not Gandalf the wandering Wizard...
...who made such excellent fireworks?
Old Took used to have them on
Midsummer's Eve. Heh, heh. Ahem.
No idea you were still in business.
And where else should I be?
Where else--? Ahem.
Well, I'm pleased to find you remember
something about me...
...even if it's only my fireworks.
Yes. Well, that's decided.
It'll be very good for you...
...and most amusing for me.
I shall inform the others.
Inform the who? What? No. No. No-- Wait.
We do not want any adventures here,
thank you. Not today. Not--
I suggest you try Over the Hill
or Across the Water.
Good morning.
[GANDALF HUMMING]
[SNIFFS]
[HOBBITS CHATTERING IN DISTANCE]
[SIGHS]
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Dwalin, at your service.
Hm. Uh...
Bilbo Baggins, at yours.
Do we know each other?
No.
Which way, laddie? Is it down here?
Is what down where?
Supper.
He said there'd be food and lots of it.
He-- He said? Who said?
DWALIN:
Mmm.
Very good, this. Any more?
What? Oh, yes, yes. Ah.
Help yourself.
Hmm. It's just that, um,
I wasn't expecting company.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
That'll be the door.
Balin, at your service.
- Good evening.
- Yes. Yes, it is.
- Though I think it might rain later.
- Hm?
Am I late?
Late for what?
Oh! Ha, ha! Evening, brother.
[BALIN & DWALIN CHUCKLE]
By my beard, you're shorter
and wider than last we met.
BALIN:
Wider, not shorter.
Sharp enough for both of us.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
Uh, excuse me? Sorry, I hate to interrupt.
But the thing is, I'm not entirely sure
you're in the right house.
DWALIN:
Have you eaten?
It's not that I don't like visitors.
I like visitors as much as the next Hobbit.
But I do like to know them
before they come visiting.
- What is this?
- I don't know.
- I think it's cheese. Gone blue.
DWALIN: It's riddled with mold.
The thing is, I don't know either of you.
Not in the slightest.
I don't mean to be blunt,
but I had to speak my mind.
- I'm sorry.
BALIN: You think--?
[CLEARS THROAT]
Apology accepted.
- Ah.
- Now, fill it up, brother, don't stint.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
DWALIN: You wanna get stuck in?
- I could eat again if you insist, brother.
[WHIMPERS]
- Fili.
- And Kili.
[IN UNISON]
At your service.
- You must be Mr. Boggins.
- Nope! You can't come in.
- You've come to the wrong house.
- What?
- Has it been canceled?
- No one told us.
- No, nothing's been canceled.
- That's a relief.
Careful with these.
I just had them sharpened.
- It's nice, this place.
FILI: Yeah.
- Did you do it yourself?
- No, it's been in the family for years.
That's my mother's glory box.
Can you please not do that?
Fili, Kili. Come on, give us a hand.
Mr. Dwalin. Ha, ha.
BALIN: Shove this in the hallway.
Otherwise we'll never get everyone in.
BILBO: "Everyone"? How many more are there?
DWALIN: Where do you want this?
DWALIN: It's really heavy.
- Oh, no. No. No. There's nobody home!
Go away and bother somebody else.
There's far too many Dwarves
in my dining room as it is.
If this is some
clot-head's idea of a joke...
...I can only say it is in very poor taste.
[GRUNTING]
GLOIN:
Get off, you big lump!
[DWARVES CHATTERING]
Gandalf.
Those are my pri--! Excuse me, not my wine.
Put that back. Put that back.
Not the jam, please.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
It's a tad excessive, isn't it?
Have you got a cheese knife?
- "Cheese knife"? He eats it by the block.
BILBO: Ugh.
No, that's Grandpa Mungo's chair--
No, so is that. Take it back, please.
- I cannot hear what you're saying.
BILBO: It's an antique. Not for sitting on.
That is a book, not a coaster.
And put that map down.
- Excuse me, Mr. Gandalf?
- Yes?
May I tempt you with a cup of chamomile?
Oh, no, thank you, Dori.
A little red wine for me, I think.
NORI: Whoop! Mind out.
- Yes. Ah.
Uh, Fili, Kili. Uh...
Oin, Gloin.
Dwalin, Balin, Bifur, Bofur, Bombur...
- ...Dori, Nori. Ori!
- No. Not my prizewinners, thank you.
No, thank you.
[SPEAKS IN DWARVISH]
GANDALF:
Yes, you're quite right, Bifur.
We appear to be one Dwarf short.
He is late, is all. He traveled north
to a meeting of our kin. He will come.
Mr. Gandalf? A little glass of red wine,
as requested.
It's got a fruity bouquet.
GANDALF:
Oh. Cheers.
GLOIN:
Bombur's on his second leg of lamb already.
GANDALF:
Hmm.
[DWARVES CHATTERING]
DWALIN:
No chance. Not from that distance.
Bombur, catch!
[ALL CHEERING]
[DWARVES CHATTERING]
DWALIN:
Oh, you great galumphing git!
- Who wants an ale? There you go.
KILI: Over here, brother.
DWALIN:
I said have another drink. Here you go.
[ALL LAUGHING]
BOFUR:
Ale on the count of three!
One, two...
Up!
[NORI BELCHES]
[ALL LAUGHING]
[BELCHES]
BOFUR:
I knew you had it in you!
Excuse me, that is a doily, not a dishcloth.
- But it's full of holes.
- It's supposed to look like that. It's crochet.
And a wonderful game it is too,
if you've got the balls for it.
Bebother and confusticate these Dwarves!
My dear Bilbo, what on earth is the matter?
What's the matter?
I'm surrounded by Dwarves.
What are they doing here?
Oh, they're quite a merry gathering
once you get used to them.
I don't want to get used to them.
Look at the state of my kitchen.
There's mud trod into the carpet.
They've pillaged the pantry.
I'm not gonna tell you what
they've done in the bathroom.
They've all but destroyed the plumbing. I don't
understand what they're doing in my house!
Excuse me. I'm sorry to interrupt,
but what should I do with my plate?
FILI:
Here you go, Ori. Give it to me.
Take that back. Excuse me.
That's my mother's West Farthing pottery.
It's over 100 years old!
And can you not do that? You'll blunt them.
BOFUR:
Ooh. Do you hear that, lads?
He says we'll blunt the knives.
[SINGING]
Blunt the knives, bend the forks
Smash the bottles and burn the corks
Chip the glasses and crack the plates
That's what Bilbo Baggins hates
Cut the cloth, tread on the fat
Leave the bones on the bedroom mat
Pour the milk on the pantry floor
Splash the wine on every door
Dump the crocks in a boiling bowl
Pound them up with a thumping pole
When you're finished, if they are whole
Send them down the hall to roll
That's what Bilbo Baggins hates
[ALL LAUGHING]
GANDALF:
Bilbo.
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
He is here.
Gandalf.
I thought you said this place
would be easy to find.
I lost my way, twice.
I wouldn't have found it at all
had it not been for that mark on the door.
Mark? There's no mark on that door.
It was painted a week ago.
There is a mark. I put it there myself.
Bilbo Baggins, allow me to introduce
the leader of our company:
Thorin Oakenshield.
So...
...this is the Hobbit.
Tell me, Mr. Baggins,
have you done much fighting?
- Pardon me?
THORIN: Ax or sword?
What's your weapon of choice?
Well, I do have some skill at conkers,
if you must know...
...but I fail to see why that's relevant.
Thought as much.
He looks more like a grocer than a burglar.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
What news from the meeting in Ered Luin?
Did they all come?
- Aye. Envoys from all seven kingdoms.
BALIN: All of them!
DWALIN: And what did the Dwarves
of the Iron Hills say?
Is Dain with us?
They will not come.
[ALL MURMURING]
THORIN:
They say this quest is ours and ours alone.
BILBO:
You're going on a quest?
Bilbo, my dear fellow,
let us have a little more light.
Far to the east...
...over ranges and rivers...
...beyond woodlands and wastelands...
...lies a single, solitary peak.
"The Lonely Mountain."
GLOIN: Aye, Oin has read the portents,
and the portents say it is time.
Ravens have been seen flying back
to the mountain, as it was foretold.
"When the birds of yore return to Erebor...
...the reign of the beast will end."
Uh, what beast?
That would be a reference
to Smaug the Terrible...
...chiefest and greatest
calamity of our age.
Airborne fire-breather.
Teeth like razors, claws like meat hooks.
- Extremely fond of precious metals.
- Yes, I know what a dragon is.
I'm not afraid. I'm up for it.
I'll give him a taste of Dwarfish iron
right up his jacksie!
NORI: Good lad, Ori!
- Sit down.
BALIN: The task would be difficult
enough with an army behind us...
...but we number just 13.
And not 13 of the best...
...nor brightest.
NORI:
Here, who are you calling dim?
OIN:
Sorry, what did he say?
FILI:
We may be few in number...
...but we're fighters, all of us,
to the last Dwarf.
- And you forget,
we have a Wizard in our company.
Gandalf will have killed
hundreds of dragons in his time.
Oh, well, no. I wouldn't say--
DORI: How many, then?
- What?
Well, how many dragons have you killed?
[COUGHS]
Go on. Give us a number.
[ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
Excuse me. Please.
[SHOUTS IN DWARVISH]
If we have read these signs do you
not think others will have read them too?
Rumors have begun to spread.
The dragon, Smaug,
has not been seen for 60 years.
Eyes look east to the mountain, assessing...
...wondering, weighing the risk.
Perhaps the vast wealth of our people
now lies unprotected.
Do we sit back while others claim
what is rightfully ours?
Or do we seize this chance
to take back Erebor?
[ALL CHEERING]
BALIN:
You forget, the Front Gate is sealed.
There is no way into the mountain.
That, my dear Balin, is not entirely true.
How came you by this?
It was given to me by your father.
By Thrain. For safekeeping.
It is yours now.
FILI:
If there is a key...
...there must be a door.
These runes speak of a hidden
passage to the Lower Halls.
There's another way in.
Well, if we can find it,
but Dwarf doors are invisible when closed.
[GANDALF SIGHS]
The answer lies hidden somewhere
in this map...
...and I do not have the skill to find it.
But there are others in Middle-earth
who can.
The task I have in mind
will require a great deal of stealth...
...and no small amount of courage.
But if we are careful and clever,
I believe that it can be done.
That's why we need a burglar.
Hmm. And a good one too.
An expert, I'd imagine.
GLOIN:
And are you?
Am I what?
He said he's an expert. Hey.
Me? No. No, no, no. I'm not a burglar.
I've never stolen a thing in my life.
Well, I'm afraid I have to agree
with Mr. Baggins.
He's hardly burglar material.
Nope.
Aye, the Wild is no place for gentle folk who
can neither fight nor fend for themselves.
KILI:
He's just fine.
[CHATTERING]
Enough!
If I say Bilbo Baggins is a burglar,
then a burglar he is.
Hobbits are remarkably light on their feet.
In fact, they can pass unseen by most,
if they choose.
And, while the dragon is accustomed
to the smell of Dwarf...
...the scent of a Hobbit is all but unknown
to him which gives us a distinct advantage.
You asked me to find the 14th member of
this company and I have chosen Mr. Baggins.
There's a lot more to him
than appearances suggest.
And he's got a great deal more to offer
than any of you know.
Including himself.
You must trust me on this.
Very well.
- We will do it your way.
- No, no.
THORIN: Give him the contract.
- We're in. We're off.
BALIN: It's just the usual.
Summary of out-of-pocket expenses...
...time required, remuneration...
...funeral arrangements, so forth.
Funeral arrangements?
[BILBO SIGHS]
I cannot guarantee his safety.
Understood.
Nor will I be responsible for his fate.
Agreed.
"Terms: Cash on delivery, up to but not
exceeding one-fourteenth of total profit...
...if any." Hmm. Seems fair.
"Present company shall not be liable
for injuries inflicted by...
...or sustained as a consequence thereof,
including, but not limited to lacerations...
...evisceration..."
Incineration?
Oh aye. He'll melt the flesh off
your bones in the blink of an eye.
[WHIMPERS]
- You all right, laddie?
- Huh? Yeah.
Feel a bit faint.
- Think furnace with wings.
BILBO: Air... I--I need air.
Flash of light, searing pain, then poof.
You're nothing more than a pile of ash.
BILBO:
Hmm.
Nope.
GANDALF:
Oh, very helpful, Bofur.
I'll be all right.
Just let me sit quietly for a moment.
You've been sitting
quietly for far too long.
Tell me, when did doilies
and your mother's dishes...
...become so important to you?
I remember a young Hobbit who was always
running off in search of Elves in the woods.
Who would stay out late,
come home after dark...
...trailing mud and twigs and fireflies.
A young Hobbit who would have liked
nothing better...
...than to find out what was beyond
the borders of the Shire.
The world is not in your books and maps.
It's out there.
I can't just go running off into the blue.
I am a Baggins of Bag End.
You are also a Took.
Did you know that your great-great-
great-great-uncle Bullroarer Took...
...was so large, he could ride a real horse?
- Yes.
- Yes, well, he could.
In the Battle of Green Fields,
he charged the Goblin ranks.
He swung his club so hard, it knocked
the Goblin king's head clean off...
...and it sailed a 100 yards through the air
and went down a rabbit hole.
And thus, the battle was won.
And the game of golf invented
at the same time.
I do believe you made that up.
Well, all good stories
deserve embellishment.
You'll have a tale or two to tell
of your own when you come back.
Can you promise that I will come back?
No.
And if you do...
...you will not be the same.
That's what I thought.
Sorry, Gandalf, I can't sign this.
You've got the wrong Hobbit.
It appears we have lost our burglar.
Probably for the best.
The odds were always against us.
After all, what are we?
Merchants, miners...
...tinkers, toy-makers.
Heh, heh. Hardly the stuff of legend.
There are a few warriors amongst us.
Old warriors.
I would take each and every one
of these Dwarves...
...over an army from the Iron Hills.
For when I called upon them,
they answered.
Loyalty, honor...
...a willing heart.
I can ask no more than that.
You don't have to do this.
You have a choice.
You've done honorably by our people.
You have built a new life for us
in the Blue Mountains.
A life of peace and plenty.
A life that is worth more than
all the gold in Erebor.
From my grandfather to my father,
this has come to me.
They dreamt of the day when the Dwarves
of Erebor would reclaim their homeland.
There is no choice, Balin.
Not for me.
Then we are with you, laddie.
We will see it done.
[DWARVES HUMMING]
[SINGING]
Far over the misty mountains cold
To dungeons deep
And caverns old
We must away
'Ere break of day
To find our long-forgotten gold
The pines were roaring on the height
The winds were moaning in the night
The fire was red, it flaming spread
The trees like torches blazed with light
[MOANS]
Hello?
Yes.
[CHICKENS CLUCKING]
WORRYWORT:
Here, Mr. Bilbo, where are you off to?
- Can't stop, I'm already late!
- Late for what?
I'm going on an adventure!
DORI: I said it. Didn't I say it?
Coming here was a waste of time.
GLOIN:
That's true enough.
DORI: Ridiculous notion. Use a Hobbit?
A Halfling?
Whose idea was it anyway?
BILBO:
Wait!
THORIN:
Whoa, whoa.
[PONIES NEIGHING]
I signed it.
Here.
[PONY SNORTS]
BALIN:
Everything appears to be in order.
Welcome, Master Baggins...
...to the company of Thorin Oakenshield.
[ALL CHUCKLING AND CHATTERING]
Give him a pony.
No, no, that won't be necessary.
Thank you. I'm sure I can keep up on foot.
I've done my fair share of walking holidays,
you know?
Even got as far as Frogmorton once. Aah!
[NEIGHS]
OIN:
Come on, Nori. Pay up.
KILI: One more.
OIN: Thanks, lad.
What's that about?
Oh, they took wagers
on whether or not you'd turn up.
Most of them bet that you wouldn't.
And what did you think?
Well...
My dear fellow,
I never doubted you for a second.
[SNEEZES THEN SIGHS]
It's horse hair. Having a reaction.
[GROANS]
No, wait, wait, stop.
Stop! We have to turn around.
GANDALF:
What on earth is the matter?
- I forgot my handkerchief.
BOFUR: Here.
Use this.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
THORIN:
Move on.
GANDALF: You'll have to manage
without pocket handkerchiefs...
...and a good many other things,
Bilbo Baggins...
...before we reach our journey's end.
You were born to the rolling hills
and little rivers of the Shire.
But home is now behind you.
The world is ahead.
[SNORING]
Hello, girl. Who's a good girl?
It's our little secret, Myrtle.
You must tell no one. Shh, shh.
[SCREECHING IN DISTANCE]
What was that?
Orcs.
Orcs?
Throat-cutters.
There'll be dozens of them out there.
The lone-lands are crawling with them.
They strike in the wee small hours
when everyone's asleep.
Quick and quiet, no screams.
Just lots of blood.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
THORIN:
You think that's funny?
You think a night raid by Orcs is a joke?
We didn't mean anything by it.
THORIN:
No, you didn't.
You know nothing of the world.
BALIN:
Don't mind him, laddie.
Thorin has more cause than most
to hate Orcs.
After the dragon took the Lonely Mountain...
...King Thror tried to reclaim
the ancient Dwarf kingdom of Moria.
But our enemy had got there first.
Moria had been taken by legions of Orcs...
...led by the most vile of all their race:
Azog the Defiler.
The giant Gundabad Orc...
...had sworn to wipe out the line of Durin.
He began...
...by beheading the king.
[ROARING]
No!
BALIN: Thrain, Thorin's father,
was driven mad by grief.
He went missing. Taken prisoner or killed...
...we did not know.
We were leaderless.
Defeat and death...
...were upon us.
That is when I saw him.
A young Dwarf prince...
...facing down the pale Orc.
He stood alone against this terrible foe.
[AZOG ROARS]
His armor rent...
...wielding nothing but an oaken branch
as a shield.
[THORIN YELLS]
[AZOG SCREAMING]
Azog the Defiler learned that day...
...that the line of Durin
would not be so easily broken.
[THORIN SHOUTING IN DWARVISH]
[ALL YELLING]
Our forces rallied...
...and drove the Orcs back.
And our enemy...
...had been defeated.
But there was no feast...
...nor song that night...
...for our dead
were beyond the count of grief.
We few had survived.
And I thought to myself then...
...there is one who I could follow.
There is one...
...I could call king.
And the pale Orc?
What happened to him?
He slunk back into the hole
whence he came.
That filth died of his wounds long ago.