KILI:
Come on! Get up!
- Bilbo!
- Don't!
Lay down your arms...
...or we'll rip his off.
[SWORD CLANGS]
NORI:
Oh! That's hot, that's hot, that's hot!
Don't bother cooking them.
Let's just sit on them
and squash them into jelly.
They should be sautéed and grilled
with a sprinkle of sage.
BALIN:
Is this really necessary?
That does sound quite nice.
BOMBUR: Untie me, mister.
GLOIN: Eat someone your own size.
WILLIAM:
Never mind the seasoning.
We ain't got all night.
Dawn ain't far away.
Let's get a move on.
I don't fancy being turned to stone.
BILBO:
Wait!
You are making a terrible mistake.
You can't reason with
them. They're half-wits!
Half-wits? What does that make us?
I meant with the seasoning.
What about the seasoning?
Well, have you smelt them?
You're gonna need something stronger
than sage before you plate this lot up.
BOMBUR: Traitor!
- What do you know about cooking Dwarf?
BERT:
Shut up. Let the flurgaburburahobbit talk.
The secret to cooking Dwarf is...
BERT: Yes? Come on. Tell us the secret.
- It's, uh...
Yes, I'm telling you. The secret is...
...to skin them first.
NORI:
What? Skin us?
Tom, get me filleting knife.
I'll skin you, you little--!
DWALIN:
I won't forget that. I won't forget it.
What a load of rubbish.
I've eaten plenty with their skins on.
Scarf them, I say, boots and all.
TOM:
He's right.
Nothing wrong with a bit of raw Dwarf.
Nice and crunchy.
Oh, not that one. He's infected.
- Huh?
- You what?
Yeah, he's got worms in his... tubes.
TOM: Eww!
BOMBUR: Aah!
In fact, they all have.
They're infested with parasites.
It's a terrible business.
I wouldn't risk it. I really wouldn't.
Parasites? Did he say "parasites"?
We don't have parasites. You have parasites!
OIN:
What are you talking about, laddie?
[KILI GRUNTS]
I've got parasites as big as my arm.
Mine are the biggest parasites.
I've got huge parasites.
[DWARVES CHATTERING]
KILI: We're riddled.
ORI: Yes, I'm riddled.
Yes, we are, badly.
What would you have us do, then?
Let them all go?
- Well...
- You think I don't know what you're up to?
This little ferret is taking us for fools.
- Ferret?
- Fools?
GANDALF:
The dawn will take you all!
- Who's that?
- No idea.
Can we eat him too?
[TROLLS GROANING]
[ALL LAUGHING]
Get your foot out of my back.
[GRUNTING]
[DWARVES CHATTERING]
[IMITATES TROLL GROAN]
Where did you go to, if I may ask?
To look ahead.
- What brought you back?
- Looking behind.
Nasty business.
Still, they're all in one piece.
No thanks to your burglar.
He had the nous to play for time.
None of the rest of you thought of that.