Where do you think you're going?
Back to Rivendell.
No, no, you can't turn back now, eh?
You're part of the company.
You're one of us.
I'm not, though, am I?
Thorin said I should never
have come and he was right.
I'm not a Took, I'm a Baggins.
I don't know what I was thinking.
- I should never have run out my door.
- You're homesick. I understand.
No, you don't. You don't understand.
None of you do.
You're Dwarves.
You're used to this life.
To living on the road, never settling
in one place, not belonging anywhere!
Oh, I am sorry. I didn't--
[CLEARS THROAT]
No, you're right.
We don't belong anywhere.
I wish you all the luck in the world.
I really do.
What's that?
BILBO:
Hmm?
Wake up! Wake up!
Whoa!
[ALL GRUNTING AND SCREAMING]
Look out! Look out!
DORI:
Get away!
[GOBLINS GROWLING]
GLOIN:
Filthy scum!
DWALIN:
Get back!
GLOIN:
You'll pay for this!
Got you.
DORI:
All right, all right. Don't push.
DWALIN: Get off! Get your hands off me!
Get off me!
[GOBLINS GROWLING]
[BILBO GASPS THEN GOBLIN GROWLS]
[BILBO YELLING]
[GOBLINS GROWLING]
Who would be so bold
as to come armed into my kingdom?
Spies? Thieves? Assassins?
Dwarves, Your Malevolence.
Dwarves?
We found them on the Front Porch.
Well, don't just stand there. Search them.
Every crack. Every crevice.
What are you doing in these parts?
Speak!
Very well. If they will not talk,
we'll make them squawk.
Bring up the mangler.
Bring up the bonebreaker.