Not my horse! I need it!
[DWARVES MURMUR]
You're not leaving us?
I would not do this unless I had to.
You've changed...
...Bilbo Baggins.
You're not the same Hobbit
as the one who left the Shire.
I was going to tell you.
I...
...found something in the Goblin tunnels.
Found what?
What did you find?
My courage.
Good. Well, that's good.
You'll need it.
I'll be waiting for you at the overlook,
before the slopes of Erebor.
Keep the map and key safe.
Do not enter that mountain without me.
This is not the Greenwood of old.
The very air of the forest
is heavy with illusion.
It'll seek to enter your mind
and lead you astray.
"Lead us astray"?
What does that mean?
GANDALF:
You must stay on the path. Do not leave it.
If you do, you'll never find it again.
No matter what may come,
stay on the path!
Come on. We must reach the mountain
before the sun sets on Durin's Day.
BILBO: Durin's Day?
BOFUR: Let's go.
THORIN: It is our one chance
to find the hidden door.
THORIN:
The path turns this way.
This way.
BOFUR:
Air. I need air.
OIN:
My head...
...it's swimming!
What's happening?
Keep moving.
Nori...
...why have we stopped?
The path... It's disappeared.
DWALIN:
What's going on?
OIN:
We've lost the path!
THORIN:
Find it.
All of you, look. Look for the path!
[GROANS]
I don't remember this bit.
None of it's familiar.
DORI:
It's got to be here.
THORIN:
What hour is it?
I do not know. I do not even know
what day it is.
THORIN:
Is there no end to this accursed forest?!
VOICE [WHISPERING]:
Attercop.
- Look.
- A tobacco pouch.
There's Dwarves in these woods.
Dwarves from the Blue Mountains,
no less.
This is exactly the same as mine.
Because it is yours. Do you understand?
We're going around in circles.
We are lost.
THORIN:
We are not lost. We keep heading east.
OIN:
But which way is east? We've lost the sun.
DWALIN:
I thought you were the expert.
The sun.
We have to find the sun.
Up there.
We need to get above the canopy.
[DWARVES CLAMORING]
[VOICES WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY]
THORIN:
What was that?
Enough! Quiet! All of you!
[WHISPERING]
We're being watched.
[SIGHS]
[CHUCKLES]
I can see a lake!
And a river.
And the Lonely Mountain.
We're almost there!
Can you hear me?
I know which way to go!
[BRANCHES SNAPPING]
Hello?
[BRANCHES CONTINUE SNAPPING]
Hello.
Oh, no.
Oh, come on.
[YELLS]
[CHITTERS]
[ROARS]
[BILBO SCREAMS]
SPIDER 1:
Kill them! Kill them.
Eat them now,
while their blood is running.
SPIDER 2: Their hide is tough,
but there's good juice inside.
SPIDER 1: Stick it again.
Stick it again. Finish it off.
SPIDER 2:
The meat's alive and kicking!
SPIDER 1:
Kill him. Kill them now.
Let us feast.
Feast! Feast!
SPIDER 3:
SPIDER 4:
Eat them alive!
Feast!
[STICK CLATTERS]
SPIDER 2: What is it?
SPIDER 1: What is it?
SPIDER 4:
Eat them alive!
SPIDER 3:
Fat and juicy.
Just a little taste.
[HISSING]
Curse it! Where is it?! Where is it?!
Here.
Ah! It stings! It stings!
Sting.
That's a good name.
GLOIN:
You all right there, Bofur?
BALIN: I'm all right!
THORIN: Get it off me!
BOFUR:
Where's Bilbo?
BILBO:
I'm up here!
[BILBO YELLS]
[BILBO SCREAMS]
[DWARVES CLAMOR]