GLOIN: Again!
BALIN: Leave it!
There's no way out!
This is no Orc dungeon.
These are the Halls
of the Woodland Realm.
No one leaves here
but by the king's consent.
THRANDUIL: Some may imagine
that a noble quest is at hand.
A quest to reclaim a homeland,
and slay a dragon.
I myself suspect a more prosaic motive.
Attempted burglary.
Or something of that ilk.
You have found a way in.
You seek that which would
bestow upon you the right to rule.
The King's Jewel.
The Arkenstone.
It is precious to you beyond measure.
I understand that.
There are gems in the mountain
that I too desire.
White gems of pure starlight.
I offer you my help.
I am listening.
I will let you go...
...if you but return what is mine.
THORIN: A favor for a favor.
THRANDUIL: You have my word.
One king to another.
I would not trust Thranduil...
...the great king, to honor his word...
...should the end of all days
be upon us!
You, who lack all honor.
I have seen how you treat your friends.
We came to you once, starving, homeless...
...seeking your help.
But you turned your back!
You turned away from
the suffering of my people...
...and the inferno that destroyed us.
[SPEAKS IN DWARVISH]
Do not talk to me of dragon fire.
I know its wrath and ruin.
[INHALES]
I have faced the great
serpents of the North.
I warned your grandfather of
what his greed would summon.
But he would not listen.
You are just like him.
Stay here if you will, and rot.
A hundred years is a mere
blink in the life of an Elf.
I'm patient.
I can wait.
- Did he offer you a deal?
- He did.
I told him he could go
îsh kakhfê ai-'d dûr-rugnu!
Him and all his kin!
Well, that's that, then.
A deal was our only hope.