BARD:
Do it again...
...and you're dead.
BALIN:
Excuse me...
...but you're from Lake-town,
if I'm not mistaken.
That barge over there...
...it wouldn't be available for hire,
by any chance?
What makes you think I would help you?
Those boots have seen better days.
As has that coat.
No doubt you have
some hungry mouths to feed.
How many bairns?
A boy and two girls.
And your wife, I imagine she's a beauty.
BARD:
Aye.
She was.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to--
Oh, come on, come on.
Enough of the niceties.
What's your hurry?
What's it to you?
I would like to know who you are...
...and what you are doing in these lands.
We are simple merchants
from the Blue Mountains...
...journeying to see our kin
in the Iron Hills.
Simple merchants, you say?
We need food...
...supplies, weapons.
Can you help us?
BARD:
I know where these barrels came from.
What of it?
I don't know what business you had
with the Elves...
...but I don't think it ended well.
No one enters Lake-town
but by leave of the Master.
All his wealth comes from trade
with the Woodland Realm.
He would see you in irons before
risking the wrath of King Thranduil.
Offer him more.
BALIN: I'll wager there are
ways to enter that town unseen.
Aye.
But for that...
...you would need a smuggler.
For which we would pay double.