BILBO: Can you see anything?
OIN [WHISPERING]: Shh! Keep it down.
THORIN [WHISPERING]: As soon as we have the
weapons, we make straight for the mountain.
Go, go, go!
DORI [WHISPERING]:
Go, Nori.
Next.
- You all right?
- I can manage.
Let's just get out of here.
[GRUNTS]
[ALL HEAR WEAPONS CLATTERING]
[GUARDS SHOUTING IN DISTANCE]
Run!
GLOIN:
Quickly! Move now!
[GRUNTS]
[YELLING]
Get off me! Get off!
GUARD:
Move them along here.
BRAGA:
Move on!
What is the meaning of this?
BRAGA:
We caught them stealing weapons, sire.
MASTER:
Ah. Enemies of the state, eh?
ALFRID: A desperate bunch of mercenaries,
if ever there was, sire.
Hold your tongue!
You do not know to whom you speak.
This is no common criminal.
This is Thorin...
...son of Thrain, son of Thror!
[CROWD MURMURING]
We are the Dwarves of Erebor.
We have come to reclaim our homeland.
I remember this town
in the great days of old.
Fleets of boats lay at harbor...
...filled with silks and fine gems.
This was no forsaken town on a lake.
This was the center of all trade
in the North!
I would see those days return.
I would relight the great forges
of the Dwarves...
...and send wealth and riches flowing
once more from the Halls of Erebor!
[CHEERING]
BARD:
Death!
That is what you will bring upon us!
Dragon fire and ruin.
If you waken that beast...
...it will destroy us all.
THORIN:
You can listen to this naysayer...
...but I promise you this:
If we succeed...
...all will share in the wealth
of the mountain.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
You will have enough gold to
rebuild Esgaroth 10 times over!
[CROWD CHEERS]
All of you!
Listen to me!
You must listen! Have you
forgotten what happened to Dale?
Have you forgotten those
who died in the firestorm?!
And for what purpose?
The blind ambition of a Mountain King...
...so riven by greed,
he could not see beyond his own desire!
MASTER:
Now, now!
We must not, any of us...
...be too quick to lay blame.
Let us not forget that it was Girion,
Lord of Dale...
...your ancestor...
...who failed to kill the beast!
ALFRID:
It's true, sire.
We all know the story.
Arrow after arrow, he shot.
Each one missing its mark.
You have no right.
No right to enter that mountain.
I have the only right.
I speak to the Master
of the Men of the Lake.
Will you see the prophecy fulfilled?
Will you share in the
great wealth of our people?
What say you?
I say unto you...
Welcome!
And thrice welcome...
...King Under the Mountain!